{"_id": "5d48a94e", "question": "What is the best advice your parent(s) gave you? Mine was “Silence is golden”, “different strokes for different folks” and “live and let live”.", "answers": "Hi Andrea, — Your parents gave you three pieces of very good advice. Lucky you! I particularly had the “Live and Let Live” custom printed on a t-shirt that I wore, back in the 70's.\nMy step-dad once told me, “It's just as easy to marry a rich man as it is a poor one.” Well, it may be, if you throw love out of the equasion. He was young when he said that to me.\nMy dad told me, “Where there's a will, there's a way.” That advice has served me well, except for one nearly fatal experience, which I reported on in detail in another post, yesterday. I don't know if you are able to access other posts I have made.\nLastly, at a very young age, someone said to me, “Don't believe anything you hear, and only half of what you see.” That comment was likely intended more as a joke rather than sound advice. However, I've put it to discretionary good use and find there is a lot of truth in it."}
{"_id": "c7e5884e", "question": "Is there any lifestyle (including food) you could have changed to help prevent your stroke? What stroke prevention advice can you offer us seniors?", "answers": "Whole-food plant-based diet without refined or processed food, and very little or no oil not only prevents cardiovascular diseases but it can also reverse it. The plant-based diet should not include any animal protein including dairy and eggs. Dr. Caldwell Esselstyn, Director of Cardiovascular Disease Prevention and Reversal Program at the Cleveland Clinic has actually reversed arterial plaque buildup in his patients by changing the diet, as shown in the angiographic evidence below. Image A is shows the original plaque buildup and image B is after being on a whole-food plant-based diet for 32 months\nSuch a reversal is unbelievable to most doctors who believe that once you get the disease, only option is to keep taking pills (to manage it), or if the blockage gets severe, the only option is surgery, for example bypass surgery in case of coronary arteries.\nYou may want to look at my answer to a similar question on Quora for more information here. Ramesh Kakkad's answer to Will atherosclerosis go away if you change your diet?"}
{"_id": "28be0976", "question": "Does the latest medical advice suggest taking aspirin and calling 911 at the first signs of a stroke?", "answers": "For any kind of stroke, hemorrhagic, ischemic, or a TIA \"Mini stroke\" calling 911 as soon as possible is probably the single best thing you can do.\nFor much the same reasons aspirin's anticoagulant effects help during a heart attack, if you're experiencing an ischemic stroke, that is a stroke being caused by a clot in your blood stream that gets caught in a vessel in your brain, then aspirin would probably be great. After all its pretty much the exact same concept as what's happening in a heart attack (just in the brain instead). And a Transient Ischemic Attack (TIA) or \"mini-stroke\" is an ischemic stroke where the clot causing the problems simply dislodged on its own allowing blood flow to return before permanent damage sets in. The clot(s) (and the underlying conditions causing them) are still floating around waiting to get stuck again, and next time you might not be so lucky as to have it dislodge on its own again. That's why TIA's are treated so serious, and why even if the stroke symptoms reverse you should still seek emergency help sooner rather than later.\nHowever, for a hemorrhagic stroke, the opposite is true. Unlike an ischemic stroke caused by a clot, a hemorrhagic stroke is caused by a hemorrhage, or bleed in the brain. In that case you WANT your blood to clot up to stop the bleeding. Taking an anti-coagulant like aspirin or any other blood thinner will only destroy whatever clots stopping the bleed have formed, making the bleeding, and the strike itself, that much worse.\nThe problem is that short of a CT scan, there's no reliable way to tell which kind of stoke you're having. Even doctors in the Emergency Room with access to powerful clot busting medicine won't give it until they get the scans back. Why? The clot buster that will save an ischemic stroke patient will kill a hemorrhagic stroke patient. If the doctor in the ER can't tell the difference without the scanner, us EMTs and Paramedics in the field certainly cant, and neither can non medically trained patients and their families. While over the counter aspirin is no where near as powerful as TPA clot busters, unless you're experiencing the Transient mini strokes typically caused by clots, I'd personally say hold off and simply call 911."}
{"_id": "2211c346", "question": "I saw people sharing something about how making someone bleed with a needle can save them if they have a brain stroke. How wrong/dangerous is this advice?", "answers": "This hoax has been around since at least 2012\n. It’s rubbish. Yuk!!\nInterestingly enough, in grown-up medical centres around the world, if:\nYou come to hospital early on with your stroke;\nThe stroke is due to an embolism (a clot lodging in a blood vessel in the brain);\nOther circumstances are favourable …\n… there’s now a good chance you can have an endovascular clot retrieval.\nThis procedure (when used well) has been shown to have a huge effect in improving outcomes after stroke. At my hospital we’ve seen magnificent results.\nIf you want to learn about the details, read: Revolution in acute ischaemic\nstroke\ncare: a practical guide to mechanical thrombectomy\n(warning: it’s pretty technical). The above image of a retrieved clot is from this source.\nDon’t muck around with Chinese witch-doctoring when really good therapy is at hand.\nMy 2c, Jo."}
{"_id": "859aeb44", "question": "Lately, it feels like I'm poking the cue ball instead of stroking it, any advice on this?", "answers": "As others have said, they key is follow-through. You are not just striking a single point on the cue ball and completing your stroke after impact, you are always “pushing” your cue through the space where the cue once occupied. This will allow you to stay accurate (follow through straight) and impart english/follow/draw on the cue as the tip relies on continued impact and friction. Even when you want to get a “soft” shot, you still need to follow-through. Just stroke slower and with less force - but utilize the same follow-through stroke.\nWhen you feel the urge to “poke” the cue, ask yourself why you are doing it. Oftentimes we tentatively poke at something when we are not committed to it. So, before you even get down in position, decide if it’s the right shot you want to make, visualize how it will happen and then align yourself to take the shot. Just think about how you need to stroke the cue and how. Don’t think about where the cue ball will be going afterward or let your mind wander. Just focus on doing this one shot as well as you can and do it. Your “poking” tendencies should stop once you commit fully."}
{"_id": "469b55d2", "question": "What's the latest medical advice related to post-warning stroke treatment for elderly men?", "answers": "Various people are suffering from a stroke issue, and due to the advancement of medical science, there are a couple of post warning stroke treatment options for elderly men.\nIf the TIA (which stands for transient ischaemic attack) for stroke patient does not have severe carotid atherosclerosis that may be much beneficial as compared to surgery or atrial fibrillation which needs anticoagulation, then antiplatelet therapy along with aspirin, aspirin combined with dipyridamole, or clopidogrel is mainly recommended unless there is a significant risk for bleeding complications.\nCombination of both, i.e. aspirin and clopidogrel is not supported, and the reason is that it enhances the risk of bleeding. There are underlying risk factors such as an increase in the blood pressure or diabetes that should be controlled. The therapy of lipid-lowering should be maximized, and an individual need to quit smoking needs to be initiated too, in case the person is into smoking."}
{"_id": "75792474", "question": "How do I avoid heart disease with a long family history of heart attacks and stroke?", "answers": "He is just 45 years old, healthy, no traditional risk factors like diabetes, hypertension, dyslipidemia. He never smoked, and did regular exercise. He was not overweight.\nHe was worried that he might have heart disease.\n-\nWe examined him, did the basic work-up like ECG, echocardiogram and a treadmill exercise test. Everything came out as normal. We told him that he was fine and sent him with a good dose of encouragement.\nClearly, it didn’t work.\nHe came back with symptoms that suggested anxiety.\nAnd then we found out the reason.\nHis father and uncle had suffered from heart attack at age 50. One uncle had bypass surgery at age 52. Another uncle died suddenly at night, presumably of an heart attack. His grandfather had stroke.\nA larger dose of encouragement and placebo did not do any good.\nHe came back again and again, forcing us to do a ‘64-slice-CT-Angio’ which also turned out to be normal.\nThe nervous young man was given counselling by the psychologist, but still visits us once a month.\n‘I have bad genes, sir’ he says. ‘It’s my fate’.\n-\nOf all the cardiac risk factors, diabetes, hypertension, high cholesterol or smoking, one that inculcates a feeling of fear and helplessness is family history.\nYou can’t cut, delete or undo it.\nThere is no known therapy for it.\nRight? Wrong.\n-\nGene and Environment\nA strong family history of heart attacks, even in the absence of other risk factors makes the person more susceptible to a heart attack.\nIt is not just genes that matter, family members tend to share the same environment; the same diet, the same laziness to exercise; the appreciation of the chubby look, the same callous attitude to medical checkup; also has a large supply of prescription medications.\nIn contrast, a family that exercises regularly, eat healthy; laugh together and remain healthy.\n-\nProof\n‘Pima Indians’ living in Arizona, has one of the highest prevalence of Diabetes – roughly 40% of the population have Diabetes.\nA small group of Pima Indians are also found in the mountainous region of Sierra Nevada of Mexico. Many believe that the Arizona Pima are those who migrated north for better pastures.\nStudies confirmed that both Mexican and American Pima’s are genetically similar. It was not surprising. But what was surprising was this\nWhile US Pimas had a diabetic prevalence of 40%, the Mexican Pimas had diabetes in only 7% people.\nRed Circle - Mexican Pima\nRed Arrow - American Pima\nThe reason ?\nHard working Mexican Pima\nThe Mexican Pima do hard manual work in the field, toiling whole day while the American ones got a headstart with mechanical transport, formal education, fast food and modern lifestyle; unboxing a latent ‘genetic’ diabetes.\nThe gene was quarantined for good in the Mexicans by hard work and a rustic lifestyle.\nA gene is a manual, a instructional code written deep inside your cell. How it expresses is determined, in a large way, by the environment you live in, the way you carry yourself.\nYou can shove the code book in the attic; or let it auto-pilot your life.\nYour Choice"}
{"_id": "44cd8415", "question": "9 months after suffering a hemorrhagic stroke, I'm starting back to work tomorrow (short hours & light work) any good advice for me?", "answers": "Congratulations on your survival and recovery! I too returned to work after a hemorrhagic stroke. I took a ride share there and back. Coming home, it was especially important because I was often exhausted by the day.\nPlease make sure your doctor wrote instructions and requested “accomodation” for you, including the option to reduce hours if they become too much for you. I started at two four hour days and increased my hours gradually, but some weeks, I was just exhausted and couldn’t manage to work as much as I had the week before. I got up to about 25–30 hours of work per week before I hit the wall and just couldn’t do any more.\nEverything is a bit harder. Even sitting upright in a chair is an active effort, as odd as it seems. It feels good not letting the stroke deficits define me. That said, don’t live in denial of the deficits. Accepting that things are different than they were before the stroke is an important part of recovery. I could no longer put in the 50-60 hour work weeks as I had before the stroke.\nHopefully, your employer and colleagues will be as welcoming and supportive as mine were."}
{"_id": "7e7a46ab", "question": "What useful advice can you offer someone who has a loved one recovering from a severe left brain stroke?", "answers": "First of all, I’m so sorry that they’re stuck dealing with such an unfortunate event!\nFor me, my third and final stroke, my only left-brained stroke, was the nail in my coffin. I managed to bork the OTHER side of my basal ganglia, which seems to have made me permanently exhausted. =( None of the ADD medication I took subsequent to my second stroke wakes me up anymore. It is a seemingly small, intractable, enormous problem. It sucks. I’m over it. I’m probably stuck with it for life.\nBut, in addition to my fatigue (and my increased sensitivity to sunlight and noise, my increasingly tiny handwriting, and my increasingly worse aphasia), I became depressed after my third stroke. I don’t know whether it was because people with left-brain strokes routinely become depressed or whether, after six months of dealing with this sh!t after the second stroke I was just over it, and I will never know, but man … depression sucks. I would pay good money to never, ever feel that way again. Do you remember the effect of the dementors in Harry Potter? It’s like they flew into my house and sucked out all the heat, all the love, and all the things that make life worth living. (Of course, you could also argue that’s exactly what the strokes did. You can see my confusion as to what caused the depression!)\nTwo things helped me deal with my depression: first of all, my depression led me to try Wellbutrin, which, thanks be to God!, woke me up. Not quite as spectacularly as Adderall, but it also doesn’t make me feel high all the time ;) (Which is a good thing. I feel normal on Wellbutrin.) Second of all, my husband was very up-front about it all; there was no hushed whispering about his “nutty wife”, no hesitancy to get me on medication, no reluctance to find me a counselor. I love that about him! You can certainly do that for your loved one: you can be the strong advocate for help, if they’re willing to take it.\nUnfortunately, if you’ve seen one stroke, you’ve seen one stroke — they’re so different that without more information I really can’t say, “You need a top-notch physical therapist”, “You need to go to Timbuktu to see a shaman”, or “You need to feed her lots of chocolate” — though the last one never hurts ;)\nBest of luck to you and your loved one!"}
{"_id": "27359c42", "question": "I would like to recognize tennis strokes using deep learning. What documents, theories, tools or advice will you give me?", "answers": "I approach tennis objectively. It starts with geometry. The ball will go wherever the racket is facing at contact. Then, it's about balance. You have to meet the ball in line with your lead foot to keep you from falling. Lastly, it's about physics. To maintain the weight dominance of the racket over the ball the racket should be travelling at the same speed as the ball at contact and this can only be done from a full backswing."}
{"_id": "83aba9b4", "question": "What is the best advice that people never hear about strokes?", "answers": "Patience and compassion are the keys. On everyone’s side… the survivor, the caregiver, the care team.\nI am a 2-time stroke survivor and it never seeks to amaze me how many people lose patience with the survivors for simple tasks because they have no compassion for what the survivors have been thru.\nYou will never know exactly what it’s like unless you have been thru it; but you can be a caring and compassionate human being by growing some patience.\nThank you for asking the question."}
{"_id": "842acbdd", "question": "The best advice for reducing muscle spasticity/rigidity in stroke patients?", "answers": "Overall? That would be reducing or eliminating the inflammation process after the stroke, which CAUSES more complications than the initial lesion would cause.\nWhen I had my 2nd stroke, I had it 10 minutes before reaching the ER. The ER had a very fresh MRI of a lesion. It looked like a walnut in shape and size.\n5 days later and another MRI series? A huge white field of inflammation was seen affecting 5 areas of the brain. The inflammation continued, and within 7 days I couldn’t lift my arm over my shoulder and was ataxic, and half my vision was a white light spectrum.\nThe best way to reduce complications after stroke is to curb/stop the damage from the inflammation process after the stroke. That limits the scope of the damage after the stroke.\nThe lesions of a stroke are small and local. The inflammation process though, if not contained, even grows over the days affect more areas of the brain."}
{"_id": "0e69b03b", "question": "What is your experience with long haul flights after a stroke? How was it? Is there any advice or precautions to keep in mind?", "answers": "As a nurse I can tell you that long flights are likely to *cause* strokes, because of dehydration and immobility, but after a stroke?\nBring all needed medications on a carry-on, in the original bottles. Set an alarm so you take them regularly.\nGet up to stretch every hour or two, and do calf stretching exercises in between.\nGive yourself extra time to clear Security, and be sure to ask for a wheelchair."}
{"_id": "15f3e1ef", "question": "People said 4 years ago to give the current a president chance, how come they won't heed their own advice with Biden? (Don't give me this BS about his mental state, the current president had a stroke and says a bunch of dumb things)", "answers": "Was there ever a chance given?\nRussia collusion ran from December2015 until 2019. When it was shown to be completely false.\nRemember the 100 protests in 100 days. Where every socialist nut job who didn't want to work was out protesting ?\nIn fact name 3 times CNN /NYTime reported anything positive of Trump. Remember that vaccine you wanted theres two of them. Yes Trump had the influence to speed you trials.\nSo exactly why should I give dementia Joe a chance?\nWhen he ran on stripping the 2nd Amendment\nKowtowing to China. Who is trying to replace America on the world stage. By crippling our economy.\nWho ran as far left of Sanders. Embracing socialism at every chance."}
{"_id": "9a6ff210", "question": "Im 16. My dad had a stroke a few years back, he has a horrible appetite now and I can hardly find anything to cook for him that he will enjoy. This is a long shot but does anyone have any ideas or advice?", "answers": "OK understand what he is going through because I had one. See he has changed a lot in his eating for many reasons. But the main reason is he can’t eat all that fatty food and he needs to cut out eggs and many other things so he isn’t feeling good.\nWell me I like bake fish with rice but like I said after changing food your body don’t like anything because it backs up. So you need to give him 2 things to get him ready to eat a good meal first give him oatmeal in the morning with an egg . The oatmeal will have fiber in it 2 table spoons and get him to take milk magnesia at night and in the morning. Plus a egg but not the whole egg get the cholesterol free. In fact he should have it all the time .\nSee me liked steak and pork chops and fried fish but can’t have it now. So everything is dry and it backs up. Willing to bet he was put on something for heart burn and gas. The food he use to eat kept him going so now it is backing up so he don’t feel like eating . So try that hope it helps him."}
{"_id": "0c585ec2", "question": "Do you suffer from the inability to start a two-stroke engine? If you’re a pro of small engines can you please offer solid advice?", "answers": "Fresh gasoline, with the correct oil mix. Old gas or gas with the wrong oil mix is the biggest cause of starting problems with 2 strokes.\nFull choke, pull starter rope, kick start, or push start button. Engine will start and will most likely stop.\nHalf choke then pull, kickstart, or push start button. Engine will start and remain running. Do not open the throttle or the engine will bog then die.\nWait at least 45 seconds for engine to warm up, then release choke, now you can open the throttle."}
{"_id": "7264ba7c", "question": "As a body builder for the age of 60+, how much protein must my mom have to recover leg muscles after her stroke? What is some other advice for this?", "answers": "Strokes damage brain tissue, often destroying some of it. The brain sends electricity to muscles to cause them to contract, via nerve pathways. If the leg muscles DO NOT get signals from the brain’s normal activation site anymore, they must get nerve signals from somewhere in the brain or they will cease contracting sufficiently to prevent atrophy of muscle tissue.\nWith normal digestion, any protein that previously agreed with the person before the stroke will supply sufficient protein to restore muscle mass after the stroke, IF sufficient nerve signals get to the muscles from the brain.\nThe amount of protein from normal food that built her leg muscle mass and maintained it is sufficient. Any form of sandwich & glass of milk with her normal food intake is sufficient ( vegan, vegetarian, dairy, egg, meat ) if her swallowing ability and health and appetite allow it.\nNormal food is sufficient to rebuild muscle mass, if the person can move their legs and can coordinate to walk again. It will take time to restore walking ability and coordination while the brain heals as much as it is going to heal. The signals controlling walking may have to be taken over by a different part of the brain if the brain is able to do so.\nIf the person can not walk and does not relearn walking, protein will not maintain muscle mass in the legs because the muscles are not getting enough nerve signals to maintain muscle mass and are atrophying through non use.\nRelearning old skills , including walking, after a stroke take time and daily work.\nThe daily stress is often frustrating and depressing. To combat that tendency, listening to pleasing inspiring thing for a short time each day or through out the day helps endure those feelings.\nAudio Bible & MP3 ebooks on my blog are free to use, either with speakers or headphones. I do not offer or request any contact information. I will not know if you are there.\nTenBookBucketList"}
{"_id": "9358d9cf", "question": "My dad has suffered a mid brain stroke and is unconscious for 2 months now. He is currently on both Levipil and Clonazepam. We are trying to reduce the dosage gradually to see if that will help regain his conscience. Is there any advice?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "bf9fcd87", "question": "Hey y’all! So I’m just looking for a bit of advice. So I was visiting momma at the hospital and I couldn’t help but notice a woman in the room and she had her feet poking out and I couldn’t help but feel an urge to stroke them what does this mean?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "38562180", "question": "What advice can you give to a gay top to improve his \"stroke\" during sex?", "answers": "Not 100% sure what you’re meaning by “stroke”, with your putting it in quotes.\nIn a LITERAL sense, stroke as in the thrusting of penis into anus, you should ensure that the anus muscles are relaxed and ready to receive you before penetration. This can be done with some massage during foreplay, or some insertion of smaller things such as a finger or a dildo.\nAlso, you should always lubricate. Remember - it’s not possible to OVER lubricate.\nIf anal sex causes ANY PAIN at all for the bottom, you’re not doing it right."}
{"_id": "ba822d2d", "question": "I want to try new things and new ways to jerk off and pleasure myself. Any advice on what strokes to use or where to do it?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "443a72e9", "question": "A bipolar man refuses to change his lifestyle after a stroke. Aware that choosing not to exercise, diet or follow his doctor’s advice will hasten his eventual death; is he willfully committing suicide?", "answers": ""}
